There is a quote by the famous filmmaker George Lucas that says, sound is 50% of the movie, and the
same can certainly be said for video games.
A game is fun and all the graphics are pretty cool, but it just isn't very immersive.
So let's transform our game with sound.
Firstly, we need a nice background sound for our game.
Now as we are skiing the snow, we should have some sound that makes you feel like you're skiing in
the snow.
So moving over to our state sprite, we can use this area to add our sounds.
Clicking on the sounds tab, we can move over to this button and click Upload Sound.
So now if you move over to our Sound Effects folder, you will see we have this sound called Winter
storm.
Clicking that here you can see it is not imported.
So all we need to do now is go back to our code, grab a when flag clicked and a forever loop, and
then drag in the play sound until done.
Block.
So here, as you can see, it's already selected our sound.
So all there is to do is play the game.
Now that's more like it.
It actually feels like we're in the snow.
Now, you could keep this as it is and it would be pretty cool, but we can make it even feel more exciting
by bringing in another sound, which is actually some music.
So clicking the upload sound button again and then moving over to the music folder.
Here I will choose this song here.
But you can choose whatever song you like now, because I want both my music and sound effects to play
at the same time.
I'll just duplicate this script and then change the sound to the new song that we imported.
And now all there is to do is hit play.
Now that sounds more like a game to me.
What other sound do you think we need that would really complete this?
Think about it.
Skiing and then crashing.
Yes, we need a wipeout sound.
So this time we go into our player sprite and then the sounds group click upload, then move over to
the sound effects folder.
And here you can see we have this Ski Wipeout effect.
Clicking that we can then move back to our code.
And it's quite simple really.
Basically when we touch a tree we want it to start sound ski Wipeout.
So we can just drag this block over in here.
Now let's try it hitting play and then crashing into a tree.
Well there you have it.
Subtle, but a nice touch.
So that's about it.
There's still definitely more you could do with.
Sound like a nice skiing effect.
Sound as a player turns left and right.
But I will leave all that up to you and your amazing creativity.
But as you can see or rather hear, sound is definitely 50% of the movie or in our case, the game.